ANTÓNIO HERMANO BANZE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FRONT-END

Tchumene-Estate 1, Matola-House nr. 26, Maputo Mob. +258 84 47 55 942 / +258 87 47 55 942

Mail: antoniohbanze@gmail.com



PERSONAL SUMMARY

Hey there. This is the curious and talented Antonio.

I am Web Developer with over 3 years of experience in JavaScript, Angular, Vue & React. I love being involved during every phase of the development process, including coming up with potential ideas that help different sectors to have great products. My flexible personality and natural superiority make me an excellent player in any industry. Right now I am looking for a suitable position with a company where outstanding performance is recognised and where I can work on a variety of high development projects.

Job History

• Front-End Developer

Sept, 2020 - June, 2022

InteliData Moçambique, Mozambique

InteliData is a Software and Management Consulting Group with a rapid pace development and innovative solutions for software demanding projects. I worked as a frontend developer, responsible for building, deploying and maintaining web applications for clients.

- ✓ Increased company revenue by 8% within 6 months after developing and implementing business logic for over 9 features.
- ✓ Worked with Core Java to develop automated solutions to include web interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Web services
- ✓ Collaborated with the team to design new features and enhancements of existing systems.
- ✓ Designed and Developed UI design for over 8 clients using CSS, HTML, ASP.NET, Vue, and React;
- ✓ Developed and implemented front-end solutions for web applications using modern JavaScript frameworks (Vue, React)

• Junior Web developer

June, 2019 - June, 2020

DS Solar, Mozambique

I worked as Junior web dev (Front-End) at DS Solar Mozambique, where I learned how to use Advanced state management (React context Api), Next.Js best Practices (like file-based routing, data fetching) and lastly, we have used Next.Js as back-End endpoint to built there website.

- ✓ Developed and maintained responsive user interfaces using React.js, HTML, and CSS
- ✓ Worked with business stakeholders and project managers to manage timelines and client expectations
- ✓ Participated in architectural review meetings regarding application development practices
- ✓ Set and enforced best software development practices

Education & Professional Training-Programs

- **Bsc Env. Science**I have a bacherlor degree in Physics with some computer science subjects. I found out that software is what I want to do for living.
- **Software Engineering:** Africa Leaders University / ALX Program (2022-2023 / Enrolled)
- Web Development: DS Solar Youth Program For Technology (2018)

Skills | Abilities | Competences

Expert: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJs, NodeJs, Angular, VueJS, Sass, GUI, principles of SEO, Version Control (GIT), principles of DOM, Wordpress, Bootstrap, TypeScript, SQL, Agile, Scrum.

Basics: AWS Lambda, Python, Redux, Spark, Redis, Azure DevOps

Professional

- Ability manage multiple projects in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment.
- Adaptable and able to quickly pick up new frameworks, libraries & techniques.
- Experience mentoring and managing other people
- Ability to explain technical concepts (programming/databases/stats) to nontechnical audiences
- Experience with graphic design applications | Adobe Illustrator
- Can quickly understand business requirements and then translate these into functional requirements.
- Strong client service and proactive mindset
- Strong oral and written communication skills, most importantly.

Personal

- Ability to build a sense of trust that creates a comfortable and effective workplace
- Great interpersonal and communication skills, able to easily interact with fellow developers and customers alike. Excellent analytical skills
- Strongly committed to all projects from inception right through to the end
- English: Fluent talking and perfect writing

Hobbies: Reading, Coding (JavaScript (- 80% of Time / Python-20% of Time), Traveling & Sport

On-wait for one simple opportunity.

Social:

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ant%C3%B3nio-h-banze/

GitHub: https://github.com/Antonio-H-Banze

Portfolio: https://antonio-h-banze.github.io/Antonio-Banze/